Guide to the Francis J. McNamara papers, 1928-1997
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Francis J. McNamara papers
1928-1997
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Francis J. McNamara
C0024
109.5 linear feet (215 boxes)
The Francis J. McNamara papers contains materials collected by Francis J. McNamara dating from 1928 to 1997 pertaining to American politics and culture during this period. The main concentration in this collection deals with national security with respect to the influence of Communism, the Civil Rights Movement, and the counterculture. It is comprised of newspaper and magazine articles, letters, memoranda and other personal documents, U.S. government documents, pamphlets, and other printed materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Francis J. McNamara in four deposits during the period 1995 to 1998.
Biographical Information
Francis John McNamara was born in Brooklyn, New York in 1915. After earning degrees at St. John's University in 1938 and Niagara University in 1939 (both in English), he joined the U.S. Army during World War II. He served in Asia in the China-Burma theater of operations as an intelligence officer and attained the rank of Major. After the war, married his wife of fifty-five years, Katherine Foley, and joined the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA) assisting in the Jehol and Hupeh provinces of China.
When he returned to the United States in 1948, he went to work as a researcher for American Business Consultants, Inc., in New York City, a security firm and publisher of the anticommunist newsletter Counterattack. In January of 1950 he became editor of Counterattack where he remained until May of 1954. He then moved to Washington, D.C., to head the National Security Program of the Veterans of Foreign Wars (VFW). In 1958 he left the VFW to serve as a research analyst and consultant to the House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC). In 1961 he became director of research at HUAC, and in 1962, its staff director. In 1970 he went to work for the Subversive Activities Control Board (SACB), where he served as executive secretary. In 1981 he became executive director of the Nathan Hale Foundation. He served as vice-chairman of the Security and Intelligence Foundation from 1987-90 and was a senior fellow at the Center for Intelligence Studies in Arlington, Virginia. McNamara died on February 27, 2007 at the age of 91.
Scope and Content
The Francis J. McNamara Papers represent his lifelong career and study in the field of anticommunism and national security. Materials which comprise this collection track both his employment and interests during the period 1947-1997, including his work at American Business Consultants (1948-1954), the VFW (1954-1958), HUAC(1958-1969), SACB (1970-1973), and later consulting and editing work.
Types of materials include magazine and news clippings regarding subjects of interest to McNamara; final versions of U.S. government reports pertaining to investigations of individuals and/or organizations suspected of subversive activity; manuscript notes; correspondence both to and from McNamara; and pamphlets, journals and newsletters from both the left and right sides of the political spectrum covering the period 1928 through 1997.
Main subject areas include but are not limited to: domestic and foreign communism; the Cold War (i.e. the Soviet Bloc, China, Korea, Vietnam, and Latin America); espionage and intelligence; political and cultural figures; entertainment and news media; the antiwar movement; assassinations; and domestic groups (i.e. the Black Panthers, KKK, SNCC, and the Weather Underground).
The first series covers the first half of Francis McNamara's career, with collected material roughly covering the years 1928-1975. This series contains material from McNamara's career with the House Un-American Activities Committee in Congress and later with the Subversive Activities Control Board. The second series covers the second half of Francis McNamara's career, corresponding roughly with the dates 1976-1997. This series contains material from McNamara's career at the Hale Foundation and later work. The third series, consisting of one box, contains regalia and various artifacts such as stamps, notecards, and notebooks used by McNamara.
Arrangement
Organized into three series.
Series 1: Anti-Communism and Subversive Activities, 1928-1975 (Boxes 1-154)
Series 2: National Security, 1976-1997 (Boxes 155-214)
Series 3: Regalia, 1950s (Box 215)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds a small collection of books from McNamara's personal library (283 titles in total). These can be found in the University Libraries' with a keyword search on "Francis J. McNamara Collection".
Index Terms
Persons:
McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957.; McNamara, Francis J.; Walter, Francis E. (Francis Eugene), 1894-1963.
Corporate Names:
American Civil Liberties Union.; Hale Foundation.; United States. Central Intelligence Agency.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Internal Security.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation.; United States. Subversive Activities Control Board.
Subjects:
Communism--United States--History--20th century.; Cold War--Social aspects--United States.; Espionage, American--Communist countries--History--20th century.; Hollywood (Los Angeles, Calif.)--Politics and government.; Subversive activities--United States--History--20th century.; Radicalism--United States--History--20th century.
Contents List
- Series 1: Anti-Communism and Subversive Activities, 1928-1975; (154 boxes)
  The first series covers the first half of Francis McNamara's career, with collected material roughly covering the years 1928-1975. This series contains material from McNamara's career with the House Un-American Activities Committee in Congress and later with the Subversive Activities Control Board. This series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Jabara, Abdeen, 1975-1987 (Folder 1, Box 1)
    Jabara, Abdeen, PLO, Terrorism
  - The ABM and the changed strategic military balance USA vs USSR, 1969 (Folder 2, Box 1)
    Anti-Ballistic Missile, Cold War, Military
  - Abraham Lincoln Selections from his Writings, 1944 (Folder 3, Box 1)
    Lincoln, Abraham
  - "Academic Freedom and Responsibility " Address by Herbert Brownell, Jr., April 18, 1957 (Folder 4, Box 1)
    Brownell, Herbert
  - Acheson, Dean, 1951-1953 (Folder 5, Box 1)
    Acheson, Dean
  - Acheson, Dean, 1950s (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1950s (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - ACLU, 1970-1985 (Folder 8, Box 1)
    American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)
  - ACLU, 1971-1980 (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - ACLU, 1963-1994 (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - ACLU, 1959-1979 (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - ACLU, 1975-1993 (Folder 1, Box 2)
  - ACLU, 1952-1983 (Folder 2, Box 2)
  - ACLU, 1959-1979 (Folder 3, Box 2)
  - ACLU-Anti-Intelligence, 1971-1978 (Folder 4, Box 2)
    American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), Communism, Intelligence
  - ACLU-Cities, 1952-1965 (Folder 5, Box 2)
    American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), Communism
  - ACLU-Personnel, 1959-1981 (Folder 6, Box 2)
  - ACLU-[annual] Reports, 1940-1977 (Folder 7, Box 2)
  - ACLU-[annual] Reports, 1970s (Folder 8, Box 2)
  - ACLU suits, ACLU vs. Westmoreland, 1971-1974 (Folder 9, Box 2)
  - Address by Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy to the Friendly Sons of St. Lackawanna County, Scranton, Pa., March 17, 1964 (Folder 10, Box 2)
    Kennedy, Robert F.
  - Address of Hon. Patrick J Hurley, Secretary of War at the Lincoln Day Banquet of National Republican Club. NY City., February 12, 1930 (Folder 11, Box 2)
    Republican Party, Speeches
  - Addresses, 1970-1973 (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - Aele law enforcement legal defense manual, 1974-1978 (Folder 1, Box 3)
    Americans for Effective Law Enforcement, Inc.
  - Agee, [Philip]-books, 1975-1979 (Folder 2, Box 3)
    Louis Wolf
  - Agents-esp. and influence [espionage], 1954-1994 (Folder 3, Box 3)
    Soviet Defector, Espionage
  - Agents-esp. and influence [espionage], 1960-1995 (Folder 4, Box 3)
  - Agents of influence and Wilfred Burchett, 1954-1989 (Folder 5, Box 3)
    Communism
  - Agnew [Spiro], 1969-1983 (Folder 6, Box 3)
    Agnew, Spiro
  - Agnew [Spiro], 1969-1976 (Folder 7, Box 3)
  - Agnew [Spiro], 1969 (Folder 8, Box 3)
  - Agnew [Spiro], 1969-1977 (Folder 9, Box 3)
  - AIM American Indian Movement, 1973-1995 (Folder 10, Box 3)
    Native Americans
  - Air Force - Special Operations, 1968-1971 (Folder 11, Box 3)
    Military
  - Air University, Commands and Staff College, 1961-1964 (Folder 1, Box 4)
  - A-K FIC: American-Korean Friendship Information Center, 1971-1978 (Folder 2, Box 4)
    Korea
  - Albert E. Kahn-Cedric Belfrage (agents of influence), 1951-1973 (Folder 3, Box 4)
  - Aliens, 1972-1978 (Folder 4, Box 4)
    Illegal Immigration, Migrants, Borders, Fences, Mexico
  - All American Conference, 1957-1958 (Folder 5, Box 4)
    American
  - All American Conference, 1958-1960 (Folder 6, Box 4)
  - All American Conference, 1958-1960 (Folder 7, Box 4)
  - All American Conference, 1958-1960 (Folder 8, Box 4)
  - All American Conference, 1960 (Folder 9, Box 4)
  - Alliance to End Repression, 1969-1978 (Folder 10, Box 4)
    Alliance to End Repression
  - Alliance to End Repression, 1969-1978 (Folder 1, Box 5)
  - Alliance to End Repression, 1969-1978 (Folder 2, Box 5)
  - American Bar Association, 1951-1993 (Folder 3, Box 5)
    ABA, American Bar Association
  - American Bar Association, 1951-1993 (Folder 4, Box 5)
  - American Business Consultants: Publications, 1947-1953 (Folder 5, Box 5)
    Counterattack
  - American Committee For Liberation, 1957-1960 (Folder 6, Box 5)
    American Committee For Liberation
  - American Committee For Liberation, 1957-1959 (Folder 7, Box 5)
    ACL
  - American Committee For Liberation, 1957-1960 (Folder 8, Box 5)
  - American Friends of Captive Nations, 1958-1961 (Folder 1, Box 6)
    Germany, Hungary, United Nations
  - American Legion, 1950-1963 (Folder 2, Box 6)
    Freedom's Facts
  - American Security Council, 1965-1973 (Folder 3, Box 6)
    ASC, Defense, Security
  - American Security Council, 1965-1978 (Folder 4, Box 6)
  - American Security Council, 1965-1978 (Folder 5, Box 6)
  - Americanism: It's Philosophy, Documents, and Manifestations, 1957 (Folder 6, Box 6)
  - American Youth for Democracy, 1945 (Folder 7, Box 6)
    Youth movements
  - Anatomy of a Revolutionary Movement "Students for a Democratic Society", 1970 (Folder 8, Box 6)
    Student movements
  - Anderson, Jack, 1969-1978 (Folder 9, Box 6)
    Anderson, Jack
  - Anderson, Jack, 1969-1978 (Folder 1, Box 7)
  - Anderson vs. Sills, 1970 (Folder 2, Box 7)
    Laird vs. Tatum, American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU)
  - Angola, 1975-1980 (Folder 3, Box 7)
    Cuba, Soviet Intervention, mercenary
  - Angola, 1975-1980 (Folder 4, Box 7)
  - Antiballistic Missile System, 1969 (Folder 5, Box 7)
    ABM, Nixon
  - Anti-Castro Cubans, 1975-1990 (Folder 6, Box 7)
    Terrorism, Omega 7, Alpha 66, Pragmatista, Bay of Pigs, Refugees
  - Anti-Communist groups, 1950-1956 (Folder 7, Box 7)
    Anticommunism
  - Anti-Communist Literature, 1950s (Folder 8, Box 7)
  - Anti-Communist Party groups, 1951 (Folder 9, Box 7)
    Anticommunism, Political parties
  - Anti-Communist Propaganda, 1941-1959 (Folder 10, Box 7)
  - Anti-Communist Publications, 1947-1954 (Folder 11, Box 7)
  - Anti-intellectualism, 1952-1956 (Folder 12, Box 7)
    Elmer Davis, Catholics, Eggheads
  - Anti-intelligence funding, 1970-1984 (Folder 1, Box 8)
    Unions, Philanthropy
  - Anti-intelligence legislation, 1975-1978 (Folder 2, Box 8)
    Intelligence, H. R. 10400, 95th Congress, Civil Liberties, FBI Charter
  - Anti-intelligence legislation, 1975-1978 (Folder 3, Box 8)
    H. R. 10400, 95th Congress, Civil Liberties, FBI Charter
  - Anti-intelligence legislation, 1975-1978 (Folder 4, Box 8)
  - Anti-military movies, 1961-1965 (Folder 5, Box 8)
    Seven Days in May, Strangelove, Cinema, Movies
  - Anti-military movies, 1961-1965 (Folder 6, Box 8)
  - Anti-Semitic Activity in the United States, The American Jewish Committee, 1954 (Folder 7, Box 8)
    Anti-semitism
  - Anti-"Un-American" Publications, 1939-1960 (Folder 8, Box 8)
  - [Antiwar], 1970-1971 (Folder 9, Box 8)
    Vietnam, Protests
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1966-1970 (Folder 10, Box 8)
    Vietnam, Anticommunism, Protests
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1967-1971 (Folder 11, Box 8)
    Arnold Johnson, American Servicemens Union (ASU), Protests, Vietnam
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1967-1971 (Folder 12, Box 8)
  - Anti-war, Anti-Communist, 1969-1971 (Folder 13, Box 8)
    Protests, Vietnam
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1971-1973 (Folder 14, Box 8)
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1969-1973 (Folder 1, Box 9)
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1969-1973 (Folder 2, Box 9)
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1970-1973 (Folder 3, Box 9)
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1969-1976 (Folder 4, Box 9)
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1969-1975 (Folder 5, Box 9)
    Execution of Private Slovik, Draft, Recruiting, Desertion, Protests, Vietnam
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1972-1974 (Folder 6, Box 9)
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1971-1974 (Folder 7, Box 9)
    GI Drug Use, Vietnam
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1971-1974 (Folder 8, Box 9)
    End of Draft, Recruitment, GI Drug Use, Vietnam
  - Anti-war, anti-communist, 1963-1973 (Folder 9, Box 9)
    Vietnam
  - Argentina, 1973-1975 (Folder 10, Box 9)
    Guerrillas, Peron, Argentine Civil War, Terrorism
  - Army, 1952-1953 (Folder 1, Box 10)
  - Army, 1951-1958 (Folder 2, Box 10)
  - Army, 1950s (Folder 3, Box 10)
  - Army no. 2, 1953 (Folder 4, Box 10)
  - Army no. 2, 1953 (Folder 5, Box 10)
  - Army no. 2, 1953 (Folder 6, Box 10)
  - Army "Spying", 1970-1995 (Folder 7, Box 10)
    Espionage
  - Aronson vs. Giarrusso, 1971 (Folder 1, Box 11)
    Richard Aronson, Joseph Giarrusso, New Orleans
  - Art - Fine Art, 1943-1959 (Folder 2, Box 11)
    Modern Art, Propaganda, Cultural Freedom
  - Art - Fine Art, 1943-1959 (Folder 3, Box 11)
  - Art - Fine Art, 1943-1989 (Folder 4, Box 11)
    Modern Art, Propaganda, Entertainment
  - Art - Fine Art, 1943-1989 (Folder 5, Box 11)
  - ASC (American Security Council) - miscellaneous, 1967-1981 (Folder 7, Box 11)
    American Security Council
  - ASC (American Security Council) - miscellaneous, 1967-1981 (Folder 8, Box 11)
  - ASC, SDI, 'Star Wars', 1971-1988 (Folder 9, Box 11)
    ABM, American Security Council, SALT, Strategic Defense Initiative
  - ASC, SDI, 'Star Wars' (assorted articles), 1971-1995 (Folder 10, Box 11)
    American Security Council, Strategic Defense Initiative
  - Ashbrook [John], 1968-1982 (Folder 11, Box 11)
    Ashbrook, John
  - Asian Outlook, 1965 (Folder 1, Box 12)
    Asia
  - Asian Outlook, 1966 (Folder 2, Box 12)
  - Assassination attempt - Ford, Gerald, 1975-1989 (Folder 3, Box 12)
    Sara Jane Moore, Charles Manson, Lynette Fromme
  - Assassinations - general, 1972-1994 (Folder 4, Box 12)
    Assassination
  - Assassinations - general, 1972-1994 (Folder 5, Box 12)
  - Assassination report [Fidel Castro], 1975-1981 (Folder 6, Box 12)
    Cuba, Castro
  - Assassination report [Fidel Castro], 1975-1981 (Folder 7, Box 12)
  - Assassination - Esssex, Mark, 1973-1975 (Folder 8, Box 12)
    Sniper, KKK, Ku Klux Klan
  - ASU-STAPP: the bond, 1970 (Folder 9, Box 12)
  - Atkinson [Soviet foreign policy], 1935 (Folder 10, Box 12)
    Foreign policy academic articles, Nuclear weapons, USSR
  - Atomic Bombing Survival Leaflets, 1950s (Folder 11, Box 12)
    Nuclear safety
  - Attica-prisons, 1971-1981 (Folder 12, Box 12)
    Attica, Police, Prisons
  - Attorney general's list, 1950-1978 (Folder 1, Box 13)
    Attorney General, Courts
  - Attorney general's list--court decisions, ca. 1950s (Folder 2, Box 13)
  - Attorney general's list--executive, 1947-1971 (Folder 3, Box 13)
    Attorney General
  - Attorney general's--studies and recommendations, 1950-1965 (Folder 4, Box 13)
  - Baltimore, 1971-1981 (Folder 5, Box 13)
    Baltimore, Maryland
  - BBJ-Factual [Black Bag Jobs], 1966-1978 (Folder 6, Box 13)
    Breaking and Entering, Bugging, Break-In, FBI, Espionage
  - BBJ-Factual [Black Bag Jobs], 1966-1978 (Folder 7, Box 13)
    Breaking and Entering, Bugging, Break-In, FBI
  - Berlin Democratic Club, 1973-1980 (Folder 8, Box 13)
    Wiretapping, Bugging, Germany, Espionage
  - Berrigans, 1971-1980 (Folder 9, Box 13)
    Phil Berrigan, Daniel Berrigan, Peace
  - Berrigans, 1971-1980 (Folder 10, Box 13)
    Phil Berrigan, Daniel Berrigan
  - Bicentennial [U.S.], 1974-1976 (Folder 11, Box 13)
    Protest, People's Bicentennial Commission, PBC
  - Bills [Legislative], 1970-1981 (Folder 1, Box 14)
    Terrorism
  - Bills [Legislative], 1970-1981 (Folder 2, Box 14)
  - B-informants, 1954-1980 (Folder 3, Box 14)
    FBI, INS, Nazi, KKK
  - John Birch Society, 1961 (Folder 4, Box 14)
    Robert Welch
  - Black Liberation Army [BLA], 1971-1982 (Folder 5, Box 14)
    BLA, BPP, Police, Terrorism
  - Black Liberation Army (BLA), Black Panther Party (BPP), 1970-1980 (Folder 6, Box 14)
  - Black listing treatment, 1956-1978 (Folder 7, Box 14)
    The Front, Woody Allen, Film, Cinema, Hollywood
  - Blacklisting treatment pro and con, 1951-1981 (Folder 8, Box 14)
    Film, Cinema, Hollywood, HUAC Report, Communism
  - Blacklisting treatment pro and con, 1951-1981 (Folder 9, Box 14)
  - Blacklisting treatment pro and con, 1951-1981 (Folder 9, Box 14)
  - Black Panther Party -Law suits, 1970-1981 (Folder 11, Box 14)
    Supreme Court, Hanrahan v. Hampton, FBI
  - Black revolutionary violence, 1964-1969 (Folder 12, Box 14)
    Black Panther Party, BPP
  - Bolling, [Richard]-HCIS, 1973-1975 (Folder 1, Box 15)
    House Committee on Internal Security
  - Bolling, [Richard]-HCIS, 1973-1975 (Folder 2, Box 15)
  - Bomb statistics-Explosives, 1973-1986 (Folder 3, Box 15)
    Bombings, Terrorism
  - The Bang Jensen Tragedy, May 1960 (Folder 4, Box 15)
    United Nations, UN, Paul Bang-Jensen, Hungarian Revolution, Assassination
  - Booklets published by Asian People's Anti-Communist League, 1955 (Folder 5, Box 15)
    Anti-Communism
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1956 (Folder 6, Box 15)
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1957 (Folder 7, Box 15)
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1958 (Folder 8, Box 15)
  - Booklets Published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1959 (Folder 9, Box 15)
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1960 (Folder 10, Box 15)
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1961 (Folder 11, Box 15)
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1962 (Folder 1, Box 16)
  - Booklets published by Asian Peoples' Anti-Communist League, 1964 (Folder 2, Box 16)
  - Books, 1950-1951 (Folder 3, Box 16)
    Newspaper clippings, Book review
  - Books, 1950-1952 (Folder 4, Box 16)
    Newspaper clippings, Book reviews
  - Books-anti, 1950s (Folder 5, Box 16)
    Newspaper clippings, Book reviews, pro-Communist
  - Books-anti, 1950s (Folder 6, Box 16)
  - Books-anti (file no. two), 1950s (Folder 7, Box 16)
  - Book burning, 1950s (Folder 1, Box 17)
    U.S. Overseas Libraries, Joseph McCarthy, Anti-Communism
  - Book burning, 1950s (Folder 2, Box 17)
    Joseph McCarthy, Anti-Communism
  - Books-anti-intelligence, 1973-1993 (Folder 3, Box 17)
    Expose, Non-Fiction, Fiction, Reviews, Literature, CIA, FBI
  - Books-pro-intelligence, 1950-1952 (Folder 4, Box 17)
    Non-Fiction, Fiction, Literature, Reviews
  - Books-pro-intelligence, 1950-1952 (Folder 5, Box 17)
  - Boorda-Archuleta-Holley case, 1969-1970 (Folder 6, Box 17)
    Subversive Activities Control Board vs. Simon Boorda, Robert Archuleta and Wayne Holley, Supreme Court
  - Boston, 1974-1976 (Folder 7, Box 17)
    School Busing, Desegregation, Race, Terrorism
  - Boudin, Leonard, 1971-1990 (Folder 1, Box 18)
    Lawyer, pro-Communism
  - Boycotts--Blacklist, 1972-1993 (Folder 2, Box 18)
    Media Censorship, Drugs, U.S. Business, Anti-Communism
  - Boycotts--Blacklist, 1972-1993 (Folder 3, Box 18)
  - Brainwashing, 1953-1955 (Folder 4, Box 18)
    Cold War propaganda, Arms race
  - Braverman [Maurice], 1950-1973 (Folder 5, Box 18)
  - Bremer [Arthur H.]-Wallace [George], 1972-1989 (Folder 6, Box 18)
    Assassination, Arthur Bremer Trial
  - Britain, 1960-1988 (Folder 7, Box 18)
    Espionage, USSR
  - Britain, 1960-1988 (Folder 8, Box 18)
  - Browder, Earl, 1932-1945 (Folder 9, Box 18)
    Communist Party USA, pro-Communist
  - Buchanan News, 1967 (Folder 10, Box 18)
    National Security, Detente, Cold War
  - Budget, 1972-1973 (Folder 11, Box 18)
    Subversive Activities Control Board, SACB
  - Bugs-Taps, 1950-1979 (Folder 1, Box 19)
    Wiretapping, Espionage
  - Bureau of Intelligence and Research, January 1960 (Folder 2, Box 19)
    Intelligence
  - C-A [Counterattack], 1948-1955 (Folder 3, Box 19)
    Anti-Communism, Political Affairs February 1951
  - California Bankers [Association] v. [George P.] Shultz, 1974 (Folder 4, Box 19)
    ACLU
  - Campus, students, general, 1969-1992 (Folder 5, Box 19)
    "What Businesses need to know about the Student left"
  - Campus, students, general, 1969-1992 (Folder 6, Box 19)
    Colleges, Protests
  - Campus, students, general, 1968-1974 (Folder 7, Box 19)
    Protests, Demonstration, Activism
  - Campus, students, general, 1968-1974 (Folder 8, Box 19)
  - Capitol and Pentagon bombing (Leslie Bacon, Stewart Albert, Judy Gumbo), 1971-1976 (Folder 9, Box 19)
    Bombing, Domestic terrorism
  - Capitol Police, 1975-1979 (Folder 10, Box 19)
    Police
  - Captain Howard Levy (Folder 11, Box 19)
    Levy, Howard
  - Carl Stern, 1972 (Folder 12, Box 19)
    FBI
  - Carlos (The Jackal), 1975-1995 (Folder 13, Box 19)
    Illich Ramirez Sanchez, Terrorism
  - Castro, Fidel - Cuba, 1960-1995 (Folder 15, Box 19)
    Cuban Crisis
  - Castro, Fidel - Cuba, 1960-1995 (Folder 16, Box 19)
  - Castro, Fidel - Cuba, 1960-1995 (Folder 17, Box 19)
  - Catholic Church and communism, 1960-1992 (Folder 1, Box 20)
    Communism, Religion
  - Center for Constitutional Rights, 1970-1992 (Folder 2, Box 20)
    CCR
  - Center for Constitutional Rights, 1970-1992 (Folder 3, Box 20)
  - Central Files, 1975- 1980s (Folder 4, Box 20)
    FBI, CIA, Jurisdiction, Operational Gray Areas
  - Center for Defense Information, 1973-1994 (Folder 5, Box 20)
    Anti-Communism, Anti-War, Nuclear weapons
  - Center for Marxist Education: docket no. 128-71, 1970-1973 (Folder 6, Box 20)
    Political education
  - Center for Marxist Education: docket no. 128-71, 1970-1973 (Folder 7, Box 20)
  - Center for Marxist Education (transcripts and exhibits): dockets 128-71, 1970-1973 (Folder 8, Box 20)
  - Chemical-biological weapons, 1975-1982 (Folder 9, Box 20)
    Defense, Chemical-biological warfare
  - Chicago 7 trial, 1969-1973 (Folder 10, Box 20)
    Trials, Chicago
  - Chicago 7 trial, 1969-1973 (Folder 10, Box 20)
  - Chicago PD general, 1969-1975 (Folder 1, Box 21)
    Chicago Police Department
  - Chicago PD grand jury, 1975 (Folder 2, Box 21)
  - Chicago PD [law] suits, 1974-1978 (Folder 3, Box 21)
  - Chile Refugees, 1971-1979 (Folder 4, Box 21)
    Chile
  - China - American Anti-Communist Perspective, 1950s-1960s (Folder 5, Box 21)
    People's Republic of China, Communism
  - China - Chiang's 'Positive Policy' to roll back reds, 1945 (Folder 6, Box 21)
  - China - Communist Publications, 1949-1952 (Folder 7, Box 21)
    People's Republic of China, Communsism